CV Henrik Fogelberg

Name Henrik Fogelberg

Address Näktergalsvägen 5, Båstad

Mobile +46 793 404 458

Email henrik.fogelberg@gmail.com

LinkedIn https://www.linkedin.com/in/henrikfogelberg

Profile

Henrik has a long experience of the IT industry, working in a wide range of programming languages, environments and industries. Currently he focuses on backend development in Go, SQL, AWS and DevOps. Apart from programming he has practical experience of technical project management, requirement analyses, testing, business process analyses, software architecture, technical writing and education.

Skills

- Programming Go, SQL, Node.is, Python, Ruby
- Databases
 MySQL, SQL Server, Postgres, DynamoDB, MongoDB, Redis
- Cloud

AWS (ECS Fargate, Lambdas, S3, Aurora, SQS, ElasticCache, IAM, API Gateway, Route 53, Cloudfront, Cloudformation)

- DevOps, SRE Github actions, Cloudformation, Docker, Cloudwatch, Grafana, Teraform, Kubernetes
- ToolsGit, ClickUp

Work Experience

May 2018 - present

Backend Developer at Ifrågasätt Media Sverige AB

Architecture and backend development to design, build, release and maintain a live reporting platform Direkt, which is now used by most major media companies in Sweden and a growing number around of international news outlets. Participated in the support team.

Henrik wrote the main part of the backend code in Go,My SQL and Redis. He participated in the AWS architecture and created the CI/CD pipeline using Github Actions and Cloudformation.

The system was released to production seven months after the development started. Direkt is used now by roughly 100 media outlets in Sweden, the nordics, Germany and Austria as well as the United Nations.

Henrik maintained and further developed a commenting platform Tyck, programming in Node.js, Vue and React.

Aug 2015 - April 2018

Free lance work, Tenerife

Henrik took a break from the IT-industry and did some free lance web development in Node.js, Golang, Vue, React Native and Meteor.

Dec 2012 - July 2015

Senior consultant at ÅF

Worked on the pre study, analyses, design and architecture to replace Tetra Pak's dated business critical system to calculate tubular heat exchanger dimensions.

Developer in iOS projects using Xcode and Objective-C for Luleå Lokaltrafik, Värmlandsbuss, SF bio and Eon.

Role of technical expertise in the sales process for a number of potential project contracts.

Participated in an internal project to create a staff portal for ÅF employees. The system was written in C#.Net and TSQL.

June 2011 - Dec 2012

Programmer at Itio Systems AB

Worked on a system to log construction details as a step in reducing the energy requirements of buildings. Programming in Ruby on Rails and MongoDB.

May 2007 - June 2011

Senior consultant at CSC

Maintenance of a system used for public transport, written in <u>VB.NET</u> and TSQL.

Programmer in a project to build version 2 of a payment platform for airline tickets.

Architect for a system to handle customers and contracts for a small, local electricity company. Functioned as project manager and programmer. Programming in C#.Net, Silverlight and TSQL.

Participated in building version 2 of Telenor's webbshop for mobile phones, subscriptions and services. Programming in C#.Net and TSQL. Sole responsibility of maintaining the system when the project was finished.

April 2005 - May 2007

Programmer at VA Utveckling, Växjö

Participated in developing and maintaining an application for handling municipal water pipe systems. Programming in VB6, C# and SQL.

Education

July 2003-April 2005: KY in Water technology, Laholm

September 1995-June1996: Programming, Uppsala universitet

September 1987- June 1990:History and archaeology, Uppsala universitet